Harinath Bheem Reddy

Software Engineer or Front End Developer

Mobile: 9908598014

Email: harinathbliss@gmail.com



Profile

3.8 plus years of experience as UI Developer. Very much passionate, proficient in Integrating & developing web - based projects and applications and keep myself updated with recent trends in UI. Primary focus areas include in Angular, React JS, Redux, Context API and JavaScript, **Typescript**

Experience

Quantyum Technology June 2018 – October 2020

October 2020 – October 2021

Prutech Solutions

Wipro October 2021 – Present Now

Key responsibilities included:

- Proficient in HTML5, CSS3, Java script, TypeScript, JSON, Bootstrap and Angular, React Js, Redux.
- Collaborated with team on implementing new features and UX in an Agile environment.
- Developed working prototypes from UI designs for cross-platform devices
- Explored various emerging JavaScript technologies such as Node.js, Mongo DB for future product and feature development
- Made heavy use of Chrome Developer Tools + Firebug to ensure front end code and assets were optimized and high-quality
- Implemented plug-ins to extend application functionality
- Created security roles for strict control of UI elements and functions
- Performed testing and documentation of UI and services
- Personally, utilized an informal agile system to keep development on-track in an unstructured, selfmotivated environment
- Mentored junior team members
- Taking Latest code from Version Controls such as Git and Managing Deployments by running Bamboo Plans.

Projects

Name: Mariner Finance

Role: UI Developer

Members: 15

Environment: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React JS, Node JS, Mongo DB, Git.

Description: It consists of multiple modules to manage the credit cards and loans where customer can apply for a loans & check his credit scores. The Payment history of the customer is maintained, can schedule a call or appointment with the branch. Customer can also check for offers on his loans.

Responsibilities:

- Developed powerful Single Page Application and dynamic responsive Web Application using HTML5, CSS3, React Js, JavaScript.
- Implemented latest (ES6) features like arrow functions, constants, block-scope variables and class inheritance etc.
- Working experience with version control system GIT.
- Implemented HTTP requests using AXIOS.
- Used forms like FORMIK to perform form validations both on server and client side.

Name: IR21(International Roaming)

Role: Software Engineer

Client: Telstra

Members: 5

Environment: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React JS, Redux, React MUI.

Description: It is Network Application to track the Network Services Provided by the Telstra,

It consists of different Countries and their respective Operators and their Information. Where they

Can add new operators to the country and their network information. It is basically a role based

Application consists of three roles (User, Agent, Admin)

Responsibilities:

• Responsible for developing all the UI pages using React Js, JavaScript, Bootstrap and RESTful

API.

Worked in a team, involved in developing the UI layout and frontend programming for web

application that matches requirements of Client.

Created single Page Application with loading multiple views using route services and adding

more user experience to make dynamic.

Used JavaScript and its features such as classes Created JavaScript reusable components and

services to consume REST API's using Component based architecture.

Skills

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, bootstrap 4, JavaScript, Typescript, Angular, React JS, Redux.

Web Development tools: Visual Studio Code, Git, Bamboo

Education

Bachelor in Computer Science and Engineering

Languages Known

Telugu

Hindi

• English